# **BRIAN BEHRENS**

Software Engineer

(206) 617-0153 brian@brainbrian.com brainbrian.com

2207 Brenta PI #4 Venice, CA 90291

For a more detailed resume visit <u>brainbrian.com/resume</u> or find me at <u>linkedin.com/in/brianbehrens</u>

### **PROFILE**

I'm Brian Behrens, a developer living in Venice, CA. I have been building interactive projects professionally since 2003. The bulk of my career has been centered around websites, social campaigns and webbased applications. I have focused heavily on interaction design, web standards, usability, animation, video, e-commerce and application architecture. My passion for technology is ever-evolving and I enjoy new challenges. Behind it all, I'm a problem solver who likes telling stories. In my free time you'll find me surfing, snowboarding, skateboarding, taking photos or appreciating live music.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Software Engineer - Front End, REI; Kent, WA (100% remote) - 2017-Present

Lead front end software engineer for the Classes/Events and Adventures team. Work in a continuous integrated environment with Docker, Java, Jenkins and more. Spend most of my time updating our front end systems to be written in ES6 linting standards with Vue.js components. Use build tools like webpack and dependency management on the front end is done via our private NPM repository. Unit test our shared modules with Mocha and Chai.

## Senior Interactive Developer, POP; Seattle, WA - 2015-2017

Second time working at POP. Previously wrote a large amount of ActionScript 3, building applications and animations for various clients. This time I focused heavily on JavaScript. Used Node.js on almost every project integrating Grunt, Gulp or webpack for build tools. Used frameworks/libraries like React, Angular, GreenSock, jQuery, ScrollMagic and many others. Created animations in both CSS and JavaScript. Led various server integrations, API and database development, Docker configuration and other backend duties. Developed within Node.js, Apache, .NET and AWS environments.

### Senior Web Developer, Mervin Manufacturing; Seattle, WA — 2012-2015

Led a team in development efforts and made key decisions in e-commerce infrastructure, hosting architecture and build systems. Developed new applications for users to find and customize products. Developed responsive WordPress templates for all brand sites. Researched new technologies like Angular and implemented them in production builds. Planned marketing and social initiatives. Implemented new management communication and analytic tools for team efficiencies. Set up source control infrastructure. Evaluated analytics and made informed online-business decisions.

## Senior Interface Developer, Blast Radius; Seattle, WA — 2011-2012

Managed a team of developers executing marketing initiatives for Starbucks. Brainstormed and planned technical execution on Frappuccino, Pumpkin Spice Latte and Starbucks Holiday. Planned timelines and feature specifications for technical execution. Utilized JIRA for iteration planning. Programmed MVC based Flash experiences for Starbucks Holiday and Frappuccino using ActionScript 3 and PureMVC.

# **EDUCATION**

### Milwaukee Area Technical College, Milwaukee, WI — 2001-2005

Associates Degree in Television & Video Production Associates Degree in Visual Communications

# **SKILLS**

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, React, Vue.js, Angular, webpack, Gulp, Grunt, Preprocessors, Babel, PHP, MySQL, NoSQL, Source Control (Git & SVN), WordPress, JSON, XML, Social APIs, JS Libraries (jQuery, Underscore, GreenSock), Agile Methodology, Adobe Creative Cloud, Project Estimation/Planning, Managing Development Teams, Video and Photography